alright then hi and welcome to my
好吧，然后嗨，欢迎来到我的
session on Java EE or jacquard EE or
Java EE或提花EE上的会话或
micro profile or maybe all of them a
微观概况或也许所有这些
session that's going to help you with
会议将为您提供帮助
while getting a better overview of
同时获得更好的概述
what's out there in enterprise Java as
企业Java中有什么
of today and of course to show a little
今天当然要显示一点
bit of cool demos and stuff that we can
我们可以做的一些很酷的演示和东西
do with well around Enterprise Java so
围绕Enterprise Java做得很好
hi from my side my name is Sebastian -
您好，我叫塞巴斯蒂安-
nur born and raised in Munich Germany
nur在德国慕尼黑出生和长大
and since literally two weeks I'm now
因为从字面上讲两个星期，我现在
working for this company called IBM I'm
在这个叫IBM的公司工作
a lead Java developer advocate now since
从此成为Java开发的主要倡导者
well literally 14 days ago and well I of
实际上是14天前，而我的
course happen to continue to talk on
当然碰巧继续谈
enterprise Java on enterprise software
企业软件上的企业Java
in general and a lot of cool things I
总的来说，很多很棒的东西
believe and I'm very happy to be here at
相信，我很高兴来到这里
the wrox Belgium - well tell you a
wrox比利时-好告诉你
little bit of where we are with with
我们在一起的一点点
enterprise software and specifically for
企业软件，专门用于
enterprise projects well which
企业项目做得好
technology we can build our projects
技术，我们可以建立我们的项目
upon so while a quick poll who have you
因此，在快速民意调查中谁拥有你
uses Java EE / - card EE as of today
至今使用Java EE /-card EE
hands up ok yeah most of you and who has
好吧，你们大多数人
played around I even used micro profile
我什至玩过微缩
for okay fewer people all right so I'm
好吧，没事的人少，所以我
gonna quickly show you why we enterprise
会很快向您展示我们为什么要创业
developer Java EE developers should care
开发人员Java EE开发人员应注意
about or might care about micro profile
关于或可能关心微观概况
so well first of all just a few things
很好，首先只有几件事
about Java EE the good parts at least
关于Java EE的好地方
according to this guy so Java EE ships
据这个家伙说，Java EE上市了
with a lot of things right like if we
有很多事情，例如，如果我们
take Java EE eights the current version
将Java EE修改为当前版本
for example we have many many standards
例如我们有很多标准
and of course also many things that the
当然还有很多事情
runtime support and we might not care of
运行时支持，我们可能不在乎
all about all these things right so I
所有这些事情都是正确的，所以我
mean who wants to use soap anyway right
意味着谁想反正用肥皂
or all stuff like that but we have a few
或所有类似的东西，但我们有一些
standards that we
我们的标准
we developers typically really like that
我们开发人员通常真的很喜欢
add a lot of value and that we typically
增加很多价值，而我们通常
use and need in projects right like
在项目中的使用和需求
things like CDI Jax arrests the hole
诸如CDI Jax之类的东西可以解决问题
JSON processing or binding thing
JSON处理或绑定的东西
databases transactions ejbs well the new
数据库交易ejbs很好新
version actually and things like that
版本实际上是这样的
right so this is what we typically use
对，所以这就是我们通常使用的
in our daily work as Enterprise
作为企业的日常工作
developers right so these are the good
开发人员是对的，所以这些都是好的
parts this is what makes up most of the
这是组成大部分的部分
standard as of today right but also
今天的标准，但也
admittedly there are a few things that
诚然，有几件事
are well still even Java eight missing
甚至Java八都失踪了
if we care about modern and enterprise
如果我们关心现代和企业
applications if we care about micro
如果我们在乎微应用
services and all that it's like well we
服务以及一切都好，我们
missing a few things that at least are
至少缺少一些东西
not covered from a standard perspective
从标准角度来看未涵盖
already things like resiliency right if
像弹性这样的东西，如果
you want to build something like
你想建立像
resiliency with fault tolerance or
具有容错能力或
things like circuit breakers or
诸如断路器或
bulkheads you can do that of course but
隔板当然可以，但是
you would have to implement it yourself
您将必须自己实施
in a few well few lines of codes a few
在几行代码中
classes right there are a lot of
课上有很多
examples out there and patterns how you
例子和模式如何
do that this using the Java EAP is but
使用Java EAP做到这一点，但是
still there's at least some work to do
至少还有一些工作要做
it doesn't ship out of the box as of
截至目前，它并没有开箱即用
today for example monitoring is another
例如今天的监控是另一回事
point right of course you can omit all
当然，您可以忽略所有
kind of data using a JSON format or
使用JSON格式的一种数据或
using Prometheus compatible formats but
使用Prometheus兼容格式，但
still you would have to implement at
仍然需要在
least one class or things like that
至少一堂课或类似的事情
right configuration is another part or
正确的配置是另一部分或
distributed tracing again that could be
再次进行分布式跟踪
added by a been a specific thing but not
由一个特定的事物添加，但不是
from the standard yet so that's where we
从标准来看，这就是我们
are if you look at applying Java EE
如果您考虑应用Java EE
/ - card EE perspective so for those of
/-从EE角度看，因此对于
you who have been wondering well for now
一直在想的你
Java EE and jacquard EE are very small
Java EE和提花EE很小
even actually jacquard EE will start
甚至实际上提花EE也会开始
from where an Java EE left off so for
从Java EE中断的地方开始
now they you could say mean the same
现在他们你可以说同样的意思
thing so I just wrote a Java jacquard EE
事情，所以我只写了Java提花EE
application if I solely use Java
我仅使用Java的应用程序
standards and you're not lying so that's
标准，你没有说谎，所以
that's pretty even for now
就算是现在
now how to build upon that right like
现在如何建立像这样的权利
how to fill these gaps what's missing
如何填补这些空白
and this is where Mike profile kicks in
这就是Mike个人资料加入的地方
so micro profile it started with well
因此，微轮廓始于
mostly how I see two motivations first
主要是我首先看到两个动机
of all it started during a time where
所有的一切都始于
the whole well JCP process with how Java
JCP整个流程以及Java
EE evolves was a little bit slower
EE的发展有点慢
stealth yeah well we couldn't add that
是的，是的，我们无法添加
much innovation into the whole standard
全面创新
and while we still had these few things
虽然我们还有这些东西
they were missing from the standard that
他们从标准中丢失了
things that that I just showed right
我刚刚展示的东西
so micro profile aim was aimed at a few
所以微轮廓的目标是针对一些
vendors came together and say okay we
供应商走到一起说好吧，我们
want to fill these gaps we want to
想要填补这些空白，我们想要
advance the whole ecosystem on maybe not
促进整个生态系统发展
a standard perspective but something
一个标准的观点但是
like a defector standards where multiple
就像背叛者标准，其中多个
vendors are crea upon and we can build
供应商不断发展，我们可以建立
just you know technology that add some
只要您知道技术可以增加一些
value right filling these gaps well and
正确地填补这些空白的价值
the second motivation how I see it was
我看到的第二个动机是
to at least be able to fulfill the need
至少能够满足需求
for micro micro service runtimes or in
用于微微服务运行时或
other words very slim runtimes that you
换句话说，您的运行时非常苗条
could boil down by shipping the runtime
可以通过交付运行时来精简
together with the application something
与应用程序一起
like a standalone jar or fat jar
像一个独立的罐子或肥罐
approaches that was not really supported
并非真正支持的方法
from before at least not in a
从至少不是之前
standardized way in terms of Java EE so
Java EE方面的标准化方法
that was somewhat the the second
那是第二个
motivation behind that so here we are
背后的动机，所以我们在这里
micro profile and we have well a few
微观概况，我们有一些
things that are that are inside the
里面的东西
overall umbrella as of today and again
到今天为止的整体保护伞
and very opinionated a list of the good
而且非常自以为是的清单
parts that I included a micro profile
我包含微轮廓的零件
well first of all it started out with
首先，它始于
using CDI jax-rs and JSONP which is
使用CDI jax-rs和JSONP
actually enough if you want to build
如果你想建造的话就足够了
very slim and well standalone
非常苗条且独立
applications that do state stateless
无状态的应用程序
stateless functionality plus we have now
无状态功能加上我们现在拥有
a few more things that are not as
还有一些不是
standard technologies so obvi
如此简单的标准技术
the three of them come from the Java
他们三个来自Java
umbrella already and now we add ball
已经有雨伞了，现在我们加球
configuration in the micro profile
微型配置文件中的配置
config for example or fault tolerance
例如配置或容错
metrics do monitoring and all these
指标进行监控，所有这些
things and in micro profile - oh that is
事物和微观特征-哦，那是
based on Java e8 well we have these
基于Java e8，我们有这些
these projects and a few more that well
这些项目以及其他一些项目
where we can build our applications upon
我们可以在其中构建应用程序的地方
so why do you call this the opinionated
那你为什么这么称呼
a list of the good parts well because if
好零件清单，因为如果
you look a little bit further now we
您现在再往前看一点
actually want to combine micro profile
其实想结合微轮廓
with an Java EE or at least we can
使用Java EE，或者至少我们可以
combine that why because the overall
结合为什么，因为整体
idea well of micro profile is based upon
微观轮廓的思想基础是
Java EE and Java EE technology so in
Java EE和Java EE技术如此
other words we can combine these
换句话说，我们可以结合这些
technology they work well together with
他们一起工作的技术
each other because ultimately they are
彼此，因为最终他们是
actually parts of it is Java technology
实际上其中一部分是Java技术
see the eye for example right or Jack's
例如看到右眼或杰克的眼睛
arrest Jason P and Jason B so by
逮捕Jason P和Jason B，因此
combining these technologies we can
结合这些技术，我们可以
actually fill these gaps that Java EE
实际上填补了Java EE的这些空白
still has so now in terms of development
现在在发展方面仍然如此
models like basically which things which
模特基本上喜欢哪个东西
stand us to choose right what to do what
让我们选择正确的做法
where to base our projects on so the
我们项目的基础
first option we have in as a development
作为发展的第一选择
option is to use plain Java EE / 2 card
选项是使用纯Java EE / 2卡
ie only right use the project with just
即只正确使用项目
what's inside the umbrella and we can do
雨伞里面是什么，我们可以做
that it's a lot of proven technologies
这是很多行之有效的技术
you know it includes most of the things
你知道它包括了大多数东西
that we would need and most of all many
我们将需要的，而且最重要的是
of the developers out there know the API
那里的开发人员知道API
is already right has been out there for
已经是正确的了
quite a while
一段时间
we know the standards when you know all
我们都知道标准
the annotations and things so well that
注释和东西都很好
makes a lot of sense right but as I said
很有道理，但正如我所说
we have some missing parts some gaps
我们有一些缺失的部分，一些差距
there if we on the other hand look at
如果我们从另一方面来看
micro profile if we say ok we take a
微型个人资料，如果我们说确定，我们将
different option we skip Java EE all
不同的选项，我们全部跳过Java EE
together and say we solely build our
在一起说我们完全建立我们的
applications with micro profile - oh so
微型轮廓的应用程序-哦，如此
to say so
这样说
only that then of course we end up with
只有这样，我们当然最终会
something that is well comparable II
可以媲美的东西II
slim and lightweight right we only have
苗条而轻巧的权利，我们只有
a bunch of standards to ship with this
一堆与此附带的标准
or de facto standards and only modern
或事实上的标准，只有现代
api's and stuff but actually it's hardly
api和东西，但实际上几乎没有
enough to run while production
足以在生产时运行
enterprise applications or at least
企业应用程序或至少
applications that a little bit more
应用程序多一点
complex
复杂
for example that need while transactions
例如交易时需要
or databases some kind of persistence
或数据库某种持久性
because this is not included by micro
因为这不包含在micro中
profile out of the box right by only
开箱即用
micro profile so there are few things
微观资料，所以几乎没有
that are lacking and others are
缺乏而其他人
concurrency utils at least still there
并发工具至少仍然存在
are plans to add that in micro profile
计划在微观档案中添加
also or things like timers and
还是定时器和
asynchronous behavior at least up to to
异步行为至少达到
some extent so it's also micro profile
在某种程度上也是微观的
alone is hardly enough but now my take
一个人还不够，但现在我拿走了
on that is that actually makes a lot of
那实际上是使
sense to combine these two things to
将这两件事结合起来的感觉
build our projects with plain java ee
使用普通的Java EE构建我们的项目
plus micro profile we're actually well
加上微轮廓，我们实际上很好
java he still has these gaps right so
Java的他仍然有这些差距，所以
first of all we get the proven
首先我们得到了证明
technology the known api's that we have
技术，我们拥有的已知api
in java ee plus we get all of these
在Java EE中，加上所有这些
extra benefits for what is missing in
缺少的额外好处
Java EE configuration for example right
以Java EE配置为例
resiliency or we have all the metrics
弹性还是我们拥有所有指标
and monitoring data and open tracing and
和监控数据并进行公开跟踪
in - that makes a lot of sense to
在-这很有意义
combine these technologies and not say
结合这些技术而不是说
oh we use only micro profile for example
哦，我们仅使用微轮廓
and we can also use a very similar
我们也可以使用非常相似的
development and deployment model so if
开发和部署模型，如果
we have a Java EE capable application
我们有一个支持Java EE的应用程序
server I know that word is almost almost
服务器，我知道这个词差不多
an insult these days but yeah
这些天是侮辱，但是
application server runtime with Java EE
Java EE的应用程序服务器运行时
that is also capable of running micro a
也能够运行micro a
micro profile then I would argue we get
微观概况，然后我认为我们得到了
some of the best of both worlds because
两全其美的一些，因为
we can still use that proven deployment
我们仍然可以使用经过验证的部署
model and used to Java apps re use to
建模并用于Java应用程序
micro profile projects to fill these
微型档案项目来填补这些
gaps so this is one I want to show you
差距，所以这是我要向您展示的
right now and now enough talking in
此时此刻
slides
滑梯
now let's have some live coding - time
现在让我们进行一些现场编码-时间
to wake up I have two projects here that
唤醒我这里有两个项目
I want to show you and of course because
我想给你看，当然是因为
I'm a coffee lover I call the first
我是咖啡爱好者，我称之为第一个
application it's called coffee shop and
应用程序称为咖啡店
the second one will be called barista so
第二个叫做咖啡师
we have some coffee examples here and
我们在这里有一些咖啡的例子，
what I want to show you right now is
我现在想告诉你的是
first of all just the standard
首先只是标准
standalone java ee 8 project that is
独立的Java EE 8项目
this one the coffee shop project which
这个咖啡厅项目
I'm now gonna enhance with a few things
我现在要增加一些东西
that we might want to add so this one
我们可能要添加，所以这一个
just because I'm brave runs on JDK 11
只是因为我很勇敢地在JDK 11上运行
who runs their workload on JDK 11 hands
他们在JDK 11上运行工作负载的人
up yes that's what I've thought who
是的，这就是我以为是谁
played with JDK 11 at least and so ah
至少玩过JDK 11等等
that's better
那更好
alright so this builds on JDK and
好吧，所以这是建立在JDK和
actually also runs on JDK and well thank
实际上也可以在JDK上运行，非常感谢
God it works so we gonna show this today
天哪，所以我们今天要展示
and well just briefly I want to show you
好吧，我想简单地告诉你
how what that project includes so for
该项目包括什么
now it is only Java 8 standalone and
现在只有Java 8独立版本，
basically what we have while I use
基本上我在使用时所拥有的
Jack's rest to offer some HTTP endpoints
杰克的休息提供一些HTTP端点
right what people can add some cold
对，人们可以加些感冒
coffee orders and then well we're gonna
咖啡订单，然后我们要
enhance that a little bit so first of
增强一点，所以首先
all we have our Jack's rest resource
我们只有杰克的休息资源
here where we can well get some coffee
在这里我们可以喝咖啡
orders and post them by a JSON so this
订购并通过JSON发布，因此
is as a Java EE developers usually quite
作为Java EE开发人员通常
known technology quite known api's right
已知技术众所周知api的权利
we're usually used to Jason B P to
我们通常习惯于Jason BP
include it with Jack's rest and so on
包括它和杰克的休息等等
and so forth and ultimately we will ask
等等，最终我们会问
some managed bean to please order some
一些托管豆，请订购一些
coffee and then this actually will later
咖啡，然后实际上会在以后
on I show a little bit of that later go
在以后我会展示一点
to an external system and make a call in
到外部系统并打入
a synchronous way by HTTP and we'll
通过HTTP同步方式，我们将
access that system right so a few things
正确访问该系统的几件事
that we might want to add once we add
一旦添加，我们可能想要添加
micro profile so what could be helpful
微观资料，有什么用
for example would be to add some fault
例如会增加一些错误
tolerance because what's at the
宽容是因为
dependency
依赖
here because for now let's say the HTTP
这里，因为现在让我们说HTTP
the HTTP look up to the the connection
HTTP查找连接
to the external system that might fail
到可能会失败的外部系统
right the external system might not be
正确的外部系统可能不是
available and then we for example want
可用，然后我们例如想要
to retry or at least we want want to
重试，或者至少我们想要
build in some circuit breaking behavior
内置一些断路行为
so to say right so as you can see in the
所以说正确，如你所见
dependencies here already there are a
依赖这里已经有一个
few ways how to add that and I can show
几种方法来添加它，我可以展示
you later on that we also have
您稍后，我们也有
dependencies for the overall micro
整体微观的依赖
profile umbrella that includes all of
轮廓伞，包括所有
the dependencies but that is already a
依赖关系，但这已经是
nice way I believe to start with why
我相信从为什么开始的好方法
because it is very similar to the
因为它非常类似于
development model and deployment model
开发模型和部署模型
that we have in Java EE we can actually
在Java EE中，我们实际上可以
add provided dependencies and the same
添加提供的依赖项并相同
is true for our API that is literally
对于我们的API来说确实如此
only the api's and the annotations that
只有api和
we have here by also specifying provided
我们在这里也通过指定提供
dependencies for these micro profile
这些微型配置文件的依赖性
projects so let's say we want this
项目，所以我们要这个
fault-tolerance api and then once we go
容错api，然后一旦我们去
into this coffee shop bean again and
再次进入这个咖啡厅豆
start looking into this barista thingy
开始调查这个咖啡师
that barista is basically the class that
那位咖啡师基本上就是
is the HTTP client that connects to the
是连接到
external system and for now while that
外部系统，目前
doesn't really is not really resilient
并不是真的不是真的有弹性
so we can say we want to start the
所以可以说我们想开始
coffee brewing process and do some
咖啡冲泡过程中做些
things but that might fail so let's
东西，但可能会失败，所以让我们
include a circuit breaker that's an
包括一个断路器
annotation that ships with micro profile
带有微配置文件的注释
from that package namespace and once we
从该程序包名称空间开始，一旦我们
add this this method once we annotate
注释后，请添加此方法
that method with that circuit breaker
用那个断路器的那个方法
annotation well now it is a circuit
注释很好，现在是电路
breaker which you could further
断路器，您可以进一步
configure using annotation and you can
使用注释进行配置，您可以
have a look at the at the project at the
看一下项目
specification how that exactly works
规范它是如何工作的
internally how the behavior is but from
内部行为如何，但来自
a programming model perspective that's
编程模型的观点是
already enough to specify the behavior
已经足以指定行为
so you see the programming model fits
所以您会看到适合的编程模型
into the JA ve world very well another
进入JA VE世界
thing that we might want to add is
我们可能要添加的是
configuration right and these are just
配置权，这些只是
of course made up examples here
当然是这里的例子
what I'm going to add but same story
我要补充的是相同的故事
micro profile config in version 103 is
版本103中的微型配置文件配置为
included in the all these micro profile
包含在所有这些微观配置文件中
projects and you can add this
项目，您可以添加此
individually as well like we just did of
就像我们刚才所做的那样
course always with the provided scope
当然总是在提供的范围内
why I'll show you in a few seconds and
为什么我要在几秒钟内告诉你
now we can also add some configuration
现在我们还可以添加一些配置
so for example we have a health check
例如我们进行健康检查
resource here well there's also actually
这里的资源其实也有
a health check project in market profile
市场概况中的健康检查项目
but while it's not solely or you there
但是虽然不只是你一个人
are some issues if we want to use this
如果我们想使用这个有一些问题
for for readiness behavior in
用于准备行为
applications but let's say we want to
应用程序，但假设我们要
have some configuration here right and
在这里有一些配置，
the way how this works if you for
如果您要这样做的方式
example want to read some values for
示例要读取一些值
from a properties file or from your
从属性文件或您的
environment variables you can do this as
环境变量，您可以这样做
of today with plain Java EE and you can
普通Java EE的今天，您可以
even write a thin CDI producer to be
甚至写一个瘦弱的CDI生产者
able to add inject as what I'm doing now
能够像我现在一样添加注入
for example let's say application server
例如，假设应用服务器
version something like this right but
版本类似这样的权利，但
then you would also need to add while
那么您还需要添加
some configuration and either you define
一些配置，或者您定义
your own CDI qualifiers or you use this
您自己的CDI限定词，或者您使用此
at conflict property annotation that
在冲突属性注释中
ships with micro profile config then you
附带了微配置文件配置，那么您
can simply specify place use this
可以简单地指定位置使用此
conflict property with some name the
带有某些名称的冲突属性
default name is a version showing a
默认名称是显示
second layer where that comes from
第二层是从哪里来的
that's taken from some so called default
取自一些所谓的默认值
config sources environment variables is
配置源环境变量是
one of that and that's a that we can
其中之一，那就是我们可以
simply inject that into our beans which
只需将其注入我们的豆子中
is a very nice developer experience
是非常好的开发人员体验
right we don't have to do anything else
对，我们不必做任何其他事情
because that is already covered by the
因为那已经被
implementation of our micro profile
实施我们的微型档案
specification so let's say well what
规范，所以我们说好
we're going to do with this information
我们将处理这些信息
we for example can add it to our health
例如，我们可以将其添加到我们的健康中
check resource in the HTTP header so
检查HTTP标头中的资源，以便
let's say we're going to build up a
假设我们要建立一个
response programmatically here right and
在这里以编程方式回复
say this is I mean this resource just
说这就是我的意思
says ok that's fine
说好吧
but we want to include some header some
但我们想包含一些标题
it's actually using open Liberty under
它实际上是在使用开放自由
the hood open Liberty version with app
引擎盖打开带有应用程序的Liberty版本
server version and built and return
服务器版本并生成并返回
write or do whatever you like with this
写或做任何你喜欢的
configured properties but the point is
配置的属性，但重点是
how to inject this you simply have to
如何注入这个，你只需要
inject it here and you don't have to
在这里注入它，您不必
produce as like you would have to do if
就像你必须做的那样
you would do this with plain java ee so
您可以使用纯java ee来做到这一点
that's a nice story about that and once
那是一个很好的故事
you do this that is well already enough
你这样做已经足够了
alright so these are just two examples
好了，这只是两个例子
of the many micro profile projects that
在许多微型配置文件项目中
we have that we can use to enhance our
我们有我们可以用来增强我们的
Java EE applications so what I'm going
Java EE应用程序的发展
to do with all this well of course I now
我现在当然要做好所有这些事情
want to build my application and just
想构建我的应用程序
because we can we use modern
因为我们可以使用现代
technologies such as docker containers
Docker容器等技术
and later on kubernetes and sto in a few
然后在kubernetes和sto上
moments and built our applications using
时刻，并使用
this well what do we need to do first we
这个好，我们首先需要做什么
have the project here that of course is
在这里有项目，当然是
a maven project so we kind of built this
一个Maven项目，所以我们有点建造了这个
using maven right we're gonna package
使用Maven对，我们要打包
that as well a thin waffle approach that
以及薄薄的华夫饼干方法
we have here and well that builds this
我们在这里并且很好地建立了这个
into a guava so if you are familiar with
放入番石榴，所以如果您熟悉
the thin deployment artifact approach
瘦部署工件方法
from Java EE then you might know that
从Java EE中，那么您可能知道
actually these waffles are well tiny
实际上这些华夫饼很小
just a few kilobytes because they
仅有几千字节，因为它们
actually only include the classes that
实际上只包括那些
you wrote your own business logic into
您将自己的业务逻辑写入
the wall fund and everything else is
墙基金和其他一切
provided everything else is done by the
只要其他事情都由
application server and a nice story
应用服务器和一个不错的故事
about that and specifically about
关于那个，特别是关于
runtimes that both support Java EE and
同时支持Java EE和
micro profile is you can use the same
微型个人资料可以使用相同的
approach even if you combine both
即使您将两者结合起来
technologies this is why a wrote
技术，这就是为什么写
provided here in all of these scopes so
在所有这些范围中都提供了这里
they don't actually end up in our
他们实际上并没有最终进入我们的
deployment artifact which is nice
部署工件很好
because we want to keep our moving parts
因为我们要保持运动部件
small because this will be shipped on
小，因为它将被运送到
each and every built right and you
每个建立的权利，你
rather want a ship just a few kilobyte
宁愿只几千字节的船
rather than megabyte of stuff because
而不是兆字节的东西，因为
that's included in the runtime later on
稍后将包含在运行时中
already
已经
all right that's well cute but now we
好吧，那很可爱，但是现在我们
only have to department
只需要部门
fact so what we do we need if we want to
事实如此，如果我们想要我们需要做什么
run this as a docker container well of
将其作为docker容器运行
course we need to build our docker image
当然我们需要建立我们的码头工人形象
and now what we need to do is well we
现在我们需要做的很好
need some docker image that well of
需要一些很好的码头工人形象
course includes everything that we need
课程包括我们需要的一切
in order to run right like a runtime we
为了像运行时一样运行
need a Java installation we need some
需要Java安装，我们需要一些
optional configuration or whatever but
可选配置或其他
we need also an application server that
我们还需要一个应用服务器
is capable to run or to support both
能够运行或支持两者
Java EE and micro profile and there are
Java EE和微型配置文件以及
a few out there that can do that already
几个已经可以做到的
open Liberty is one of them I ship that
开放自由是我其中的一员
using my private docker hub in a working
在工作中使用我的私人Docker集线器
that includes all of this and then we
包括所有这些，然后我们
gonna have an own server XML
将拥有自己的服务器XML
configuration for while open Liberty and
开放的Liberty和
the reason for that is I only want to
原因是我只想
specify which features we are using
指定我们正在使用哪些功能
there and of course we want to use
在那里，我们当然要使用
that's a nice story of open Liberty we
这是一个开放自由的好故事，我们
can totally configure what this should
可以完全配置这应该
be included so of course we want to use
被包括在内，所以我们当然要使用
Java 8 right that was the whole point
Java 8对了，这就是重点
plus well whatever we included micro
再加上我们包括的微
profile config and fault tolerance and
配置文件配置和容错能力以及
then also metrics we can include there
然后我们可以在其中包含指标
without even using that in our project
甚至没有在我们的项目中使用
because it ships with some nice default
因为它带有一些不错的默认值
behavior well and that's basically it
行为良好，基本上就是这样
and in our darker file and also of
在我们更黑的文件中
course we include our application and
当然，我们包括我们的应用程序和
all of this will be built into our
所有这些都将内置到我们的
docker image all right that being said
docker image没什么好说的
let's build this docker built call this
让我们构建这个docker build称为
coffee shop with some version and now
现在有某些版本的咖啡店
it's being built into a docker image
它被内置到docker映像中
right alright still boring so now we
好的，还很无聊，所以现在我们
could run this and all of that so I
可以运行所有这些，所以我
already prepared some scripts to run a
已经准备好一些脚本来运行
bunch of them because actually we have a
一堆，因为实际上我们有一个
few that will play along together so we
很少会一起玩所以我们
have to the coffee shop project and the
必须去咖啡厅项目和
barista one which I can show you in a
咖啡师，我可以给你看一个
second and actually what we can do now
第二，实际上我们现在能做些什么
is finally talk to our applique
终于和我们的贴花说话了
right that runs locally so we're gonna
正确的本地运行，所以我们要
have host 90 80 and once that is up and
拥有主机90 80，一旦启动，
running you can ask the health check
跑步可以问健康检查
resource whether all of this works let's
资源是否所有这些都可以让我们
see okay this s okay let's have a look
好的，好的，让我们看一下
at the HTTP headers and so I just use
在HTTP标头上，所以我只使用
curl right you can use any HTTP client
向右卷曲，您可以使用任何HTTP客户端
of your choice
你的选择
it's that okay for the health check
健康检查就可以了
resource oh and it also included this
资源哦，它也包括这个
HTTP header information so where does
HTTP标头信息，在哪里
that come from well actually this is an
来自好，其实这是一个
environment variable that has been set
已设置的环境变量
in my docker image so I can see the
在我的docker映像中，这样我就可以看到
version of the open Liberty server
自由Liberty服务器的版本
that's running okay that information is
信息运行正常
boring don't care about that but it's
无聊不在乎，但这是
actually more the question where does
实际上更多的问题在哪里
the information come from and how do we
信息来自以及我们如何
use it in my code that's a nice story of
在我的代码中使用它是一个很好的故事
micro profile config it well includes a
微型配置文件配置包括一个
few config sources out of the box for
开箱即用的几个配置源
example for environment variables and
环境变量和
then you just add inject and add
然后您只需添加注入并添加
conflict property them in order to get
为了获得他们而冲突的财产
into your code that's a very nice
到您的代码中，这是非常好的
programming model and you don't have to
编程模型，您不必
add anything else and that's about it
添加其他内容就可以了
for this one and of course can show you
这个当然可以告诉你
already we have this orders resource
我们已经有了这个订单资源
that is a JSON that's for now empty
这是一个JSON，现在为空
where can have my coffee orders and also
在哪里可以点我的咖啡单
if you paid a bit of tension in the code
如果您在代码中有点紧张
you will see how we can order a new
您将看到我们如何订购新的
coffee well we basically post something
咖啡好，我们基本上发布一些东西
post a JSON object to this resource and
将JSON对象发布到此资源，然后
then well it will go go through a
那么它将经历一个
business process and ultimately end up
业务流程并最终结束
at the other system in order to get our
在另一个系统上以获得我们的
coffee into the system so let's do this
咖啡加到系统中，让我们这样做
let's post some JSON to a resource here
让我们在此处向资源发布一些JSON
with well a coffee a JSON has a type
加上咖啡，JSON有一种类型
basically the type of the drink suggests
基本上，饮料的种类表明
espresso or cappuccino right and we can
浓缩咖啡或卡布奇诺咖啡，我们可以
post this to a system and then it
将此发布到系统，然后
hopefully tells us something like fine
希望能告诉我们一些类似的东西
thank you
谢谢
HTTP 201 created so that's nice that
HTTP 201的创建非常好
means that worked right as expected but
表示效果正常，但
now what's also
现在还有什么
a nice story about that is that a few
一个不错的故事是
things have been added out-of-the-box
开箱即用地添加了东西
metrics for example since we included
指标，例如，因为我们将
micro profile metrics in this in the
微型配置文件指标
applications of a comparation if you
比较应用程序，如果您
remember then this will ship with some
请记住，这将与一些
default behavior and default metrics
默认行为和默认指标
default monitoring data out of the box
开箱即用的默认监控数据
so it will include this resource that
因此它将包括该资源
looks a little bit ugly if you look at
如果你看，看起来有点难看
it player in plain text but it's
它是纯文本播放器，但是
actually a Prometheus format that just
实际上是普罗米修斯格式
ships out of the box with micro profile
带有微型轮廓的包装箱
and that is included well here in your
这很好地包含在您的
server right and if you have a look at
服务器的权利，如果你看看
it it shows some basic JVM information
它显示了一些基本的JVM信息
that's already quite helpful for example
例如，这已经很有帮助
all the threats and memory usage and if
所有威胁和内存使用情况，以及
you use market profile fault tolerance
您使用市场概况容错
what we did with our custom circuit
我们对定制电路做了什么
breaker then it will also include some
断路器，那么它还将包括一些
metrics for that out of the box so
开箱即用的指标，因此
that's very nice and let me show you um
很好，我让你看
one thing how to set it up so what I
一件事如何设置它，所以我
have I have two more containers running
我还有两个容器正在运行吗
locally one is CRO Pharma and one is
在本地一个是CRO Pharma，另一个是
Prometheus why well because Prometheus
普罗米修斯为什么很好，因为普罗米修斯
will scrape this immunity's monitoring
会削弱这种免疫力的监测
data that I just am emitted and graph on
我刚刚发出的数据并在上面绘制
awell will display it nicely so what we
好吧，它将很好地显示它，所以我们
do we just in a second that's actually a
我们在一秒钟内实际上是
stock graph fauna we will set up this
股票图动物区系，我们将建立这个
connection here from me theose and then
从我这里连接，然后
we can actually ship and display
我们可以实际运送和展示
Prometheus the data here that we have in
普罗米修斯这里的数据
fault-tolerance technology so somebody
容错技术，所以有人
created a dashboard for that already and
为此已经创建了一个仪表板，
what we have and this is really nice
我们有什么，这真的很好
out-of-the-box we get some monitoring
开箱即用，我们得到了一些监控
data and information for our micro
微观数据和信息
profile fault tolerance standard so what
概要文件容错标准
we have it will detect all of the
我们拥有它将检测所有的
methods basically all of the
方法基本上所有的
functionality that has been enhanced
增强功能
with micro profile fault tolerance for
具有微轮廓容错功能
example our start a coffee brewing
例如我们开始冲泡咖啡
process method right and then it will
处理方法正确，然后它将
more
更多
include some more data of course for now
现在包括一些更多的数据
it's boring let's add some orders let's
很无聊，让我们添加一些订单，让我们
order some more coffee
再多喝点咖啡
more coffee more coffee more coffee and
更多咖啡更多咖啡更多咖啡和
then ultimately this will end up in our
那么最终这将最终在我们
monitoring data and show that actually
监视数据并显示
now this functionality has been called
现在这个功能已经被称为
many many times and then if it would
很多很多次，然后如果
fail and the circuit breaker would trip
发生故障，断路器将跳闸
you will see is here and you get some
你会看到在这里，你会得到一些
nice information out of that more or
不错的信息，或者
less out of the box if you add micro
如果您添加微型，则开箱即用
profile metrics so and fault tolerance
剖析指标和容错能力
that's a very nice story I believe in
我相信这是一个很好的故事
order to enhance our Java EE
为了增强我们的Java EE
applications any questions for that by
对此提出任何问题
the way I forgot to forgot to mention if
我忘记提及的方式
there are any questions any time please
随时有任何疑问
feel free to ask other than that I can
随便问我
show you a slightly different approach
向您展示一种略有不同的方法
just because that development model of
只是因为那种发展模式
the second application is slightly
第二个应用略
simpler because the second application
更简单，因为第二个应用程序
our barista application is basically a
我们的咖啡师应用程序基本上是
stateless application that just accepts
仅接受的无状态应用程序
this coffee orders and then returns yes
这个咖啡订单，然后返回是
or no and that application can actually
或否，该应用程序实际上可以
be built by plain micro profile and this
由普通的微轮廓建立，这
is the pump out of that one already so
是从那一台泵中抽出来的吗
which other dependency that we have is
我们还有哪些其他依赖项
this one the micro profile dependency so
这是微观配置文件的依赖关系
without specifying a specific project
没有指定具体项目
that actually includes all of the
实际上包括所有
projects we have there so all of the
我们在那里的项目，所以所有的
micro profile projects so this one will
微型配置文件项目，因此这一项目将
solely run on micro profile which is
仅在微配置文件上运行
fine for this very example it ships with
对于这个例子很好
Jax arrests it will use JSON P actually
Jax逮捕了它实际上将使用JSON P
I can show you and then we also have a
我可以告诉你，然后我们还有一个
customized runtime for it so we have a
为此它定制了运行时
very basic Jax resource here that uses
这里使用的非常基本的Jax资源
well Jason P that's also including micro
杰森P还包括微
profile right this one will be a CDI CDI
配置文件权利，这将是CDI CDI
bean and that's basically it so what we
豆，基本上就是这样，我们
can do in our server configuration is to
在我们的服务器配置中可以做的是
say oh actually we do not even need Java
说哦，实际上我们甚至不需要Java
8 so if we skip all of that then while
8所以如果我们跳过所有这些，那么
the applications of a Stark will be a
Stark的应用将是
little bit faster because we need way
快一点，因为我们需要方法
less features we actually only need CDI
更少的功能，我们实际上只需要CDI
jacks the rest
千斤顶剩下的
see and of course we want the nice
看到，我们当然要好
features now we'll show in a second and
现在将展示的功能
then you have a slimmer runtime already
那么你已经有一个更苗条的运行时了
but just doing this server configuration
但是只是做这个服务器配置
well in the example of open Liberty and
以开放自由为例
then you can include this and ship a
那么您可以包含此内容并发送
standalone project here alright so what
这里的独立项目好吗
else I want to show you which is
否则我想告诉你
actually very nice if you run in well if
如果跑得好，如果
you run in a service mesh environment
您在服务网格环境中运行
for example ISTE oh it's the integration
例如ISTE哦，这是整合
with distributed tracing so that's one
与分布式跟踪，所以这是一个
thing I didn't show you yet how we can
我还没告诉你的事情
make the distribute and tracing work and
进行分发和跟踪工作，以及
open tracing is a micro profile project
开放式跟踪是一个微型配置文件项目
that well includes if can include a
包括如果可以包括一个
tracing information on both while the
同时跟踪信息
aim endpoint and communication level and
目标终点和沟通水平以及
also on the code level so you can
同样在代码级别，因此您可以
actually include api's and enhance this
实际上包括api并增强它
tracing context even from a code level
甚至从代码级别跟踪上下文
but it already and I think that's
但已经，我认为那是
already very helpful includes tracing
已经非常有用的包括跟踪
information that are passed as
传递的信息
correlation IDs in your HTTP headers out
HTTP标头中的相关性ID
of the box so what we can do if we
盒子里的东西，所以如果我们
include and pass in some tracing header
包含并传递一些跟踪头
information into the first resource into
信息化成第一资源
the first HTTP boundary with the
第一个HTTP边界
incoming traffic then what the
传入流量然后
application serve actually we do if we
申请服务实际上是
use open tracing it will pass on all
使用开放式跟踪将通过所有
that tracing context all the way in the
在整个过程中一直跟踪上下文
threat even if we hit an HTTP client and
即使我们命中了HTTP客户端
it will then pass on these correlation
然后它将传递这些相关性
IDs in that HTTP come a connection as
该HTTP中的ID作为一个连接
well which is very helpful because then
好，这非常有帮助，因为
we don't have to do it ourselves so in
我们不必自己做
order to give you a quick idea how we
为了让您快速了解我们
can use that and what's the benefit of
可以使用它，这有什么好处
all that I will actually show you a very
我实际上会向您展示一个非常
quick example to run these two
运行这两个示例
applications in a kubernetes and sto
kubernetes和sto中的应用程序
environment who have you has used
你曾经使用过的环境
kubernetes or and/or hto before hands up
举起手来之前使用kubernetes或和/或hto
ok very few of you so this talk of
好的，你们很少。
course is not really about
当然不是真的
nice arrest you but I think this is a
很高兴逮捕您，但我认为这是一个
very nice showcase if you're familiar
如果您熟悉的话，非常好的展示
with that technology of where it
有了它的技术
actually makes sense to add this micro
实际添加这个微型
profile specifications in of to in to
配置文件规范，从到到到
our enterprise applications to make it
我们的企业应用程序
run and work better in service mesh
在服务网格中运行并更好地工作
environments so what I have here is well
环境，所以我在这里很好
a Cuban Indies cluster or actually an
古巴印度群岛集群或实际上是
ECU enabled cluster that runs in the
启用ECU的集群在
cloud so sto is I would say the de facto
云，所以我会说事实上
standard for a service mesh technology
服务网格技术的标准
and and I use them managed kubernetes
我用它们托管的kubernetes
cluster that I enhanced with Sto
我用Sto增强的集群
here that runs in the cloud and if we
在云中运行，如果我们
are lucky then we have a proper internet
幸运的话，我们有一个适当的互联网
connection as well so what I do I
连接以及我该怎么做
basically if you interested in that you
基本上，如果您对此感兴趣
can have a look at all the code examples
可以看看所有的代码示例
and all the slides later on I actually
后来我所有的幻灯片
don't want to spend too much time on on
不想花太多时间
explaining kubernetes in Istria in this
在此解释伊斯特拉半岛的kubernetes
talk just it's actually more about the
谈论它实际上是关于
market profile integration that I will
我将进行的市场概况整合
show you in a second but what I do here
一秒钟告诉你，但我在这里做什么
I have a bunch of kubernetes and sto
我有一堆kubernetes和sto
resources that well run these two
运行这两个资源的资源
applications in a kubernetes environment
kubernetes环境中的应用程序
right the coffee shop and the barista
对着咖啡店和咖啡师
service that we have and again they are
我们拥有的服务又是
enabled with micro profile open tracing
通过微型配置文件开放式跟踪启用
and of course the monitoring and metrics
当然还有监控和指标
data we saw before and so on and so
我们之前看过的数据等等
forth
向前
and now if we run in our service mesh in
现在，如果我们在以下服务网格中运行
environment then what the service mesh
环境然后服务网格
will do or is do will do in this case
在这种情况下将做或正在做
that it will add and this tracing
它将添加和此跟踪
information for the distributive tracing
分布式跟踪的信息
out of the box and if we then fire some
开箱即用，如果我们再开一些
requests that information will be will
要求将信息
be there will be available and it will
那里将可用，它将
be passed if we because we use micro
通过，如果我们因为我们使用微型
profile open tracing in our Java EE
Java EE中的配置文件打开跟踪
application even so if we have a look at
即使我们看看
the running applications in a cluster
集群中正在运行的应用程序
now and the running services that we
现在以及我们正在运行的服务
have
有
we included two more services one for
我们还提供了另外两项服务
the coffee shop system and one for the
咖啡厅系统和一个
barista system and also we have now two
咖啡师系统，而且我们现在有两个
running instances
运行实例
and then hopefully we can let me just
然后希望我们可以让我
have to connection put forward for Yaga
必须与Yaga提出联系
for the tracing technology because I
用于追踪技术，因为我
need to show you that in a second so
需要一秒钟告诉你
let's have a look and see if that works
让我们看看是否可行
let me just connect to the sto cluster
让我连接到sto集群
and ask the coffee shop project well are
并问好咖啡厅项目是
you up and running yet right the same
你启动并运行正确
example that we had before and it says
我们以前的例子，它说
yes okay
是的，好的
that's good news and if we ask for the
这是个好消息，如果我们要求
coffee shop orders we can now order some
咖啡店订单，我们现在可以订购一些
more coffee like the same thing that we
更多的咖啡就像我们一样
did before but now it's actually running
以前做过，但现在它实际上正在运行
in the cloud in a kubernetes an sto
在kubernetes和sto中的云中
cluster right and then he is this - well
集群正确，然后他就是这个-好
order an espresso also right and then
还点一杯意式浓缩咖啡，然后
hopefully we get well an HTTP 201
希望我们能得到HTTP 201
created status all right so what we can
创造状态好吧，我们可以
do now let's order some more coffee it's
现在做，让我们再订购一些咖啡
actually use all of that is to you
实际使用所有这一切给你
information that we had
我们拥有的信息
let me just kill the old taco container
让我杀死旧的炸玉米饼容器
so we can also forward the port for
因此我们也可以将端口转发给
graph on ax because now what we actually
在斧头上画图，因为现在我们实际上
can do is use a dashboard here I'm just
可以做的就是使用仪表板
forwarding the local ports so now it's
转发本地端口，所以现在
actually a different graph on a
实际上是一个不同的图
dashboard one that is shipped by is do
装运的仪表板是
that includes well slightly different
包括略有不同
information but you will also see that
信息，但您也会看到
if you use it's actually very similar
如果您使用它实际上非常相似
idea to what we had with micro profile
微观配置的想法
here with the default behavior out of
这是默认行为
the box but that's solely sto technology
盒子，但这完全是技术
so it will show you some monitoring data
这样它将向您显示一些监控数据
also and what's more important is the
而且，更重要的是
jger UI this cute guy guy with the
jägerUI这个可爱的家伙与
german name Yaga which is a distributed
分布式的德语名称Yaga
tracing technology and that is the
跟踪技术，那就是
technology technology responsible for
技术负责
including that tracing information in
包括在
our application it basically adds a
我们的应用程序基本上增加了一个
bunch of HTTP headers with correlation
一堆具有相关性的HTTP标头
IDs
编号
and Tran and span and trace IDs there
和Tran以及跨度和跟踪ID
and then hopefully these tracing IDs
然后希望这些跟踪ID
these correlation IDs are passed to the
这些相关ID传递给
next invocation context so once we have
下一个调用上下文，所以一旦我们有了
a bunch of micro services running there
一堆在那里运行的微服务
and one is calling the other and so on
一个正在呼叫另一个，依此类推
and so forth we can actually well trace
等等，我们实际上可以很好地追踪
all of these incoming requests if we
所有这些传入请求，如果我们
pass on that information so that's
传递这些信息，以便
actually the important context here and
实际上这里的重要背景
if we then find some traces so these
如果我们再找到一些痕迹，那么这些
were a bunch of traces that I just fired
是我刚刚解雇的一堆痕迹
before by ordering my coffee then I can
在订购咖啡之前，我可以
have a look at that information and see
看看这些信息，看看
well what's actually going on here and
那么这里到底发生了什么，
by looking at that we now see that this
通过观察，我们现在看到
was a synchronous request that
是一个同步请求
originally well was invoked by going
本来很好被调用
into the cluster for the so called
进入所谓的集群
through the so called ingress gateway
通过所谓的入口网关
and ended up at the coffee shop project
并最终完成了咖啡厅项目
well that's nice but now the interesting
很好，但是现在很有趣
information is that now the coffee shop
信息是现在咖啡店
project inside.what which we saw in the
里面的项目。我们在
code is calling this barista back-end by
代码通过以下方式将此咖啡师称为后端
while including a bunch of information
同时包含大量信息
that we can have a look into this you
我们可以看看这个你
know to look into the ex request ID so
知道要查看ex请求ID，所以
that's one information that is passed
那就是传递的信息
through the HTTP headers by actually
通过实际上通过HTTP标头
correlating these requests because if we
关联这些请求，因为如果我们
would not do that if we would not
如果我们不愿意的话
include the the HTTP headers then the
包括HTTP标头，然后
straighting technology had no chance to
拉直技术没有机会
even know that these things that these
甚至知道这些东西
two HTTP requests are even correlated
两个HTTP请求甚至相关
that one cost the other and one was the
一个成本，另一个成本是
synchronous call to well call the other
同步呼叫好呼叫其他
system and then return synchronously and
系统，然后同步返回
and here we are because then you would
而在这里，因为那时你会
not know that correlation and that is
不知道这种关联，那就是
one thing that's been added by open
开放添加的一件事
tracing out of the box and that's a nice
开箱即用，这很好
story about that if you use a runtime
关于使用运行时的故事
that supports this already and in my
已经支持了这一点
eyes this is a very beneficial
眼睛这是非常有益的
technology or beneficial combination to
技术或有益的组合
do if you are in a project context where
如果您在项目环境中
you use plain Java EE as of today and
您从今天开始使用普通的Java EE，并且
say ok you have a bunch of gaps issues
说好吧，您还有很多空白问题
that you would like to address that you
您想解决的问题
would like to close and you can do so at
想要关闭，您可以在
these technologies these projects that
这些技术这些项目
are supported as of today if you use the
从今天开始，如果您使用
corresponding micro profile projects and
相应的微型档案项目和
just add them of course if you use a
当然，如果您使用
runtime that supports both in terms of
运行时在以下方面都支持
runtime and support for that what we
运行时和对此的支持
have besides other additions I will go
除其他外，我还会去
into runtime in a second there a few
一秒钟进入运行时
other things that are also well not
其他也没有的东西
quite included into Java EE or well not
是否已完全包含在Java EE中
quite made it into the umbrella Java EE
完全融入了Java EE
for example the MVC specification if you
例如MVC规范，如果您
know about that it's actually a very
知道这实际上是一个非常
very nice one if you want to do front
如果你想做一个很好的人
and well model-view-controller
以及模型视图控制器
based action based model B controller
基于动作的模型B控制器
development on a server side or J cache
服务器端或J缓存上的开发
for example another candidate and some
例如另一个候选人和一些
other community additions that will have
其他社区将拥有的
been made because of these gaps being
因为这些差距而被制造出来
still there in Java if for example
仍然在Java中，例如
porcupine or breaker as an addition made
豪猪或破碎机作为补充
by a famous guru Adam Adam bean and that
由著名的大师亚当·亚当豆
can be added into plain Java EE or
可以添加到纯Java EE或
porcupine metrics was a project I
豪猪指标是我的一个项目
contributed but other than that
做出了贡献，但除此之外
well the micro profile projects tackle
微型配置文件项目可以解决
very similar issues in that direction so
在这个方向上非常相似的问题
a question that came quite early with
一个很早就出现的问题
the whole micro profile initiative was
整个微观档案计划是
how to or should we slim down and
我们该如何减肥？
customize to runtime right in terms of
就以下方面对运行时进行自定义
do we want to make the runtime as small
我们是否希望使运行时尽可能小
as possible
尽可能
right of course first of all you would
当然首先你会
say yes that's a good idea
说是个好主意
and we only want to include the required
而且我们只想包含必需的
standards and runtime features that we
我们的标准和运行时功能
have but also it's a question you know
有，但这也是你知道的一个问题
and the train at the trade-off of time
和火车在时间上权衡
and material spend on well either you
和物质上的花销，要么你
optimize the developer development time
优化开发人员的开发时间
and experience or the runtime so for
和经验或运行时等
example if I say I take the JA v8
如果我说我参加JA v8
umbrella look at it and say okay I do
雨伞看着它，说好吧
not need this and this and this but I
不需要这个，这个和这个，但是我
need CDI and jax-rs and so on and so
需要CDI和jax-rs等
forth and now of course I could go
来了，现在我当然可以走了
and slim down my runtime to only support
并缩小我的运行时仅支持
what I need and go with that yes that's
我需要的是什么，那就是
a that's of course an optimization for
这当然是针对
that but then of course you immediately
那，那当然，你马上
have to ask the question well what's the
必须问好这个问题是什么
benefit or in other words how much time
受益或换句话说多少时间
do you spend in doing so and what do you
你花在这样做上吗？
gain and for example I typically
获得，例如我通常
actually do not care that much about the
实际上并不在乎
storage size of the image of the
图像的存储大小
resulting image of your application but
应用程序的最终图像，但是
I care a lot about the size of while the
我很在乎
moving parts after deployment artifact
部署工件后移动零件
you ship and build each and every time
您每次运送和建造
so actually if we build a docker image
所以实际上如果我们构建一个docker镜像
that we just did and say we actually now
我们只是做了，说我们现在
want to push it so we want to push let's
想推动它，所以我们想推动我们
say the barista or the coffee shop
说咖啡师或咖啡店
project that we had just do a darker
我们刚刚做得更暗的项目
push right to transfer this just as one
推权转让这就像一个
example less you then what we will see
更少的例子，那么我们将看到
and that was called jacquard EE is that
那就是所谓的提花EE
we use the so called copy and write file
我们使用所谓的复制和写入文件
system by docker and the nice story
系统由码头工人和好故事
about it it actually doesn't push
关于它实际上并没有推动
anything or well not much the whole
什么都没有，或者整体不多
image is I don't know a few hundred
形象是我不知道几百
megabyte but it only pushed what has
兆字节，但它只能推动
been changed which is the 11 kilobyte of
已更改为11 KB
Wafaa that we added and not everything
我们添加的Wafaa而非全部
else because everything else didn't
否则因为其他一切都没有
change and this is what I care about a
变化，这就是我所关心的
lot because this will actually save you
很多，因为这实际上可以节省您
a lot of time and a lot of well
很多时间很多
bandwidth by only shipping one actually
实际只运送一个带宽
changed and in order to do so you have
改变，为了做到这一点，你有
to basically support thin deployment
基本支持精简部署
artifacts only shipping was part of your
仅运送的工件是您的一部分
application and the rest is provided by
应用程序，其余的由
the runtime already and docker very much
运行时已经和码头工人
supports that model by saying everything
通过说出一切来支持该模型
else is basically put into a lower image
否则基本上放在较低的图像中
layer before right you have to base a
正确的图层之前，您必须先
runtime of your application server and
应用服务器的运行时
then you might add another bunch of
那么您可以再添加一堆
things but the very last thing you add
东西，但最后添加的东西
is your application and that's tiny
是您的应用程序，那很小
that's only your business logic because
那只是您的业务逻辑，因为
that will change a lot many many times a
这将改变很多很多次
day that will change a lot and that's
一天会发生很大变化，那是
what I what would i optimize first on to
我首先要优化什么
say optimize moving parts your
说优化您的运动部件
deployment artifacts
部署工件
and then if you want also the runtime
然后如果您还想要运行时
been saying okay we can slim down the
一直在说可以，我们可以瘦下来
base image also if we want by saving
基本图像也可以通过保存
someone's storage and maybe some little
某人的存储空间，也许还有一点
bit of memory but the the first one is
一点记忆，但是第一个是
what I would focus on first now in terms
我现在首先要关注的是
of server runtimes that support the
支持的服务器运行时
micro profile ordered alphabetically so
微型配置文件按字母顺序排列
we have open Liberty for example that
例如，我们有开放自由
supports well Java EE and micro profile
支持良好的Java EE和微型配置文件
to 200 and that is to actually for for
到200，这实际上是为了
all of them para we have Tommy um 8 I
他们所有人，我们有Tommy um 8 I
think right now in a beta or milestone
立即考虑测试版或里程碑
phase and why fly so you can use all of
阶段以及为什么飞行，以便您可以使用所有
these application server runtimes to
这些应用程序服务器运行时
basically run that model where you base
基本上在您建立模型的地方运行
on Java EE plus well whatever you need
Java EE以及您需要的任何东西
from the micro profile projects plus for
从微型配置文件项目中
example what I showed you with adding
我向您展示的示例
micro profile fault-tolerance
微轮廓容错
and configuration for example so that is
和配置例如这样
what I which well ask you to have a look
我要问你的是什么
into so as key takeaways what I would
成为关键要点
suggest in general and again this talk
一般建议，再说一次
is targeted for real word Enterprise
适用于实字企业
projects right what should we do and
正确的项目，我们应该怎么做，
enterprise project which technology
企业项目采用哪些技术
should we base our applications on so of
我们应该基于这样的应用
course it makes a lot of sense in my
当然这对我来说很有意义
eyes to use known api's to use the
眼睛使用已知的api来使用
standards that have proven themselves
证明自己的标准
well then are included in Java EE 8
那么，这些都包含在Java EE 8中
right for example CDI for example Jack's
例如CDI，例如Jack's
arrest at JP a JTA if you need
如果需要，可以在JP JTA上逮捕
persistence and all that and well think
坚持不懈，一切都好
of micro profile as an extension for
微观轮廓的扩展
Java EE this is how I or what I think is
这就是我或我认为的Java EE
the biggest advantage of having market
拥有市场的最大优势
profile is to filling these gaps that is
配置文件是为了填补这些空白
not part of Jakarta EE as of today right
截至今天还不属于Jakarta EE的一部分
there are some near awesome attempts to
有一些很棒的尝试
do that for example what I showed you
像我向你展示的那样
with micro profile config right now
立即使用微配置文件配置
there's a conflict jsr going on to
jsr发生冲突了
actually make that part of the standard
实际上成为标准的一部分
I'm actually in that expert group and we
我实际上在那个专家组中，我们
trying to well ship that as fast as
试图以最快的速度发货
possible but I mean this doesn't help
可能，但我的意思是这无济于事
you if you're in a proud
如果你感到骄傲
as of today of course and now you want
当然，从今天开始，现在您想要
to use it right away and if you don't
立即使用它，如果不使用
want to implement that yourself well you
想要很好地实现自己
can use micro profile config for example
可以使用微配置文件配置
and I would say just try to take a
我会说只是尝试
development model that fits your need
满足您需求的开发模型
for your application side if you say you
对于您的应用程序方面，如果您说
have very well I rather a simpler
很好，我更简单
application in terms of standards you
根据您的标准申请
use and you find with all of the
使用，您会发现所有
standards that are included by micro
micro包含的标准
profile already or you might have an own
个人资料已经存在，或者您可能拥有自己的个人资料
micro profile umbrella say you need this
微型个人资料伞说您需要这个
plus another Java feature but only that
加上其他Java功能，但仅此而已
and then you use a runtime that supports
然后使用支持
that set of features for example Open
这组功能，例如“打开”
Liberty by am specifying the feature set
通过指定功能集来实现自由
in a configuration that's fine too of
在也可以的配置中
course then you save some space on the
当然，您可以节省一些空间
runtime part and just pick and choose a
运行时部分，只需选择一个
model or a set of standard that fits
模型或一组适合的标准
your need for your application what
您对您的应用程序的需求
you're doing but in general I would
你在做，但总的来说我会
advise you from experience to optimize
从经验中建议您进行优化
the deployment artifacts the moving
部署工件移动
parts first before overly optimizing the
首先进行零件优化，然后再过度优化
runtime so that's that's my point of
运行时，这就是我的观点
that and that's one reason why advice
那就是为什么建议的原因之一
that model to go forth in deployment
在部署中采用的模型
artifacts
文物
whether it's Java is all wall files but
是否是Java都是墙文件，但是
a thin deployment artifact that only
精简的部署工件，仅
includes your business classes and ship
包括您的商务舱和运送
that to a runtime that well is capable
到有能力的运行时
to do so where the runtime already
在运行时已经存在的地方这样做
includes well everything last year
包括去年的一切
everything you need and all the
您需要的一切以及所有
implementations you have and then you
你拥有的实现，然后你
add your applications on top of that so
在此之上添加您的应用程序
as a possible future direction as I
作为我未来的可能方向
would see it and if you look at in my
会看到的，如果你看着我的
block I wrote a a bunch of short
块，我写了一堆短
articles on that my my personal opinion
关于我的个人看法
what we could do in order to move the
我们可以做些什么来移动
whole thing forward so I see a lot of
整个事情向前发展，所以我看到很多
potential and micro profile as well seed
潜力和微观概况以及种子
as a somewhat incubator for a future two
作为未来两个人的孵化器
card EEE standards so micro profile
卡EEE标准，所以微简介
config is a prime example for that
配置是一个典型的例子
because actually we already have a
因为实际上我们已经有一个
conflict jsr J's our 382 that will
冲突jsr J是我们的382
basically builds upon micro profile
基本上建立在微观轮廓上
config we use a lot of the features and
配置，我们使用了很多功能，
api's and annotation
api和注解
there and then try to make it a standard
在那里，然后尝试使其成为标准
and ship it with future to Carly and
并把它和未来一起运送到Carly
actually also with Java SE that's that's
实际上，对于Java SE也是如此
the idea and built a standard for what
这个想法并为什么建立了标准
has then been proven itself as a
然后证明自己是
defector standard project under the
叛逃者标准项目
micro profile project so basically
微型配置文件项目基本上
providing what's missing from future to
提供未来所缺少的
Carta II specifications or at least as
Carta II规格或至少
we have today I also see a big benefit
今天我们也看到了很大的好处
and while sharing the design principles
并分享设计原则
and the overall look and feel and
以及整体外观和感觉
developer experience that we have and
我们拥有的开发者经验和
actually that we like when using Java EE
实际上，我们喜欢使用Java EE时
for example the declarative approach of
例如，声明式方法
using annotations right you have just a
使用注释，您只有一个
method or a class and just by specifying
方法或类，只需指定
one annotation you suddenly make it a
一个注释，您突然将其设为
jax-rs resource right or you add some
jax-rs资源权利或您添加一些
circuit breaker behavior or some other
断路器行为或其他
interceptor for example and that is I
例如拦截器，那是我
think a very efficient development model
认为一个非常有效的发展模式
to look at the whole thing and MI as it
看整个东西和它的MI
makes a lot of sense to also use that
使用它也很有意义
and this is actually the case if you
实际上，如果您
look in all the micro profile projects
看所有的微型档案项目
there to use that for micro profile
在那里使用它的微观轮廓
specifications also because then you
规格还因为那时
know it feels pretty much the same if
知道如果感觉差不多
you're a Java developer and it's not
您是Java开发人员，但不是
that much new or at least it feels
那么多的新感觉，或者至少感觉到
familiar and while also we might think
熟悉的同时我们可能会认为
about defining a somewhat a process of
关于定义一个过程
all these de facto standards I mean
我指的所有这些事实上的标准
they're not called standard and the
他们不被称为标准和
micro profile but basically saying do
微观概况，但基本上说
can we define a process to go from a
我们可以定义一个流程来从
micro profile initiative and then what
微型配置文件倡议，然后是什么
has been proven itself under the
已经在
existing implementations to basically
现有的实施方式
build a craft a future potential
造船未来的潜力
jacquard ee standard out of that so
提花EE标准
that's somewhat my well impression and
那是我的好印象，
idea on that so do you have any more
关于这个的想法，你还有吗
questions on this thing else to add yeah
关于这个东西的问题还可以
well yeah the question was I mentioned
是的，我提到的问题
there were as a problems quote-unquote
存在一个问题，报价-取消报价
with the health check API so basically
使用健康检查API基本上
what my issue is with that I use a lot
我的问题是我经常使用
of container orchestration such as
诸如
kubernetes and then you would use this
kubernetes，然后您将使用它
health check resources to tell whether
健康检查资源以判断是否
your application is ready to serve some
您的应用程序已准备好服务一些
traffic and actually if you use Ajax
流量，实际上是否使用Ajax
rest-based a health check resource that
基于休息的健康检查资源
I showed then the from experience the
我从经验中展示了
micro profile health check project will
微型个人资料健康检查项目将
tell ready a little bit too early before
告诉你准备得太早
your application is properly ready and
您的应用程序已准备就绪，并且
ready to serve some traffic so just
准备服务一些流量
slightly before and that's one reason
稍早之前，这是原因之一
why I couldn't use it for that use case
为什么我不能在那个用例中使用它
but actually that's already well that's
但实际上这已经很好
already an issue there in the project
该项目已经存在问题
and we're we attempting to fix that for
我们正在尝试解决该问题
for the next version so I'm just yeah
对于下一个版本，我只是
that's why it's not included in here all
这就是为什么它不包含在这里
right yeah thanks very good question
是的，谢谢，很好的问题
other than that you could do me one
除此之外，你可以帮我一个
favor to afterwards well tell me whether
以后再告诉我是否
you liked my session so don't complain
你喜欢我的会议，所以不要抱怨
don't poo but vote used a box voting
不要大便，但要用盒子投票
mechanism to tell me whether you like
告诉我你是否喜欢的机制
your session and other than that if you
您的会话，除此之外，如果您
like to join us tonight that's actually
想今晚加入我们
very soon at 7:00 at Kelly's Irish pub
很快在7:00在凯利的爱尔兰酒吧
the IBM party you can I ask them you can
IBM派对，你可以吗？
still sign up if you don't ever have to
如果您不需要，仍然可以注册
using this link down there well and
很好地使用此链接
other than that I hope you enjoyed my
除此之外，我希望你喜欢我的
session and thank you very much for your
会议，非常感谢您的光临
attention
注意
[Applause]
[掌声]
you
您